good morning welcome to July 11th round
table and a little devastated because I
just found out that 7-eleven isn't
happening today I did a free slurpie
which is a Canadian tradition on
7-eleven but I'll work through it I'll
work through it live on camera okay
Mikey surely the worst thing to happen
did this year though everything else
free Slurpee days cancel all right so
who would like to start as to what
they've been up to with their project
what they would need from this session
Leo's not here so one of us might be
able to take the hot seat oh god I am
Leo sent me some stuff because I think
he's having issues with the sound
because he said his iPhone wasn't except
in them seem yours wasn't wasn't let
them so don't know whether any of these
have got iPhones maybe I don't know oh
yeah no it's not it's not letting them
into stream yup but he said me stop so
did you want me to read through what he
sent or do you want me to lead after
lefties it's spoken I mean it's hard for
him to be the hot seat if he's not here
I've got a roundtable update and that
makes sense but otherwise I would
imagine that him not being here it's not
gonna be very helpful even if he watches
it after but I'm totally down with doing
a project raising on his cooperative
idea at some point in time right so do
you think maybe we could get him to do
on the zoom then they'll be better for
them if it's not accepted on his iPhone
yeah right okay that muted better we'd
probably want to have them check it
first before we make a schedule meeting
because zoom and streamer used similar
tact so if it's not working for stream
yard it probably wouldn't work for them
but we should probably do our
introductions and then we can discuss
Leo's situation my microphone is
disconnecting so if I'm having trouble
then I'll just drop off maybe I should
start I actually don't have much to
share I didn't work on reason to score
that much oh I guess I was as working on
a blog post on goal I bought calm
explaining what type of questions goalie
BOTS really good at helping people work
through and I don't know if explained it
before but the older BOTS come the
personification of the reasons score
process so he's an impartial third party
that people can communicate with and
then it'll you know in doing that you
would organize the data in a way that
helps people find agreement and learn
each other's perspective at a deeper
level so I'm working on that website and
then I got a little I learned about
several side projects that I want to do
so yeah I don't know one of them is
making an app that tells you what times
of the day what hours of the day are
best to do outdoor activities like
walking and running and stuff my mom
needed that so I'm making that for her
and that's my obsession at the moment so
that's what I'm that's what I'm working
on as far as things to help with I guess
when I get done with that blog post
maybe I'll share it and see if anyone
has any feedback on where it's clear or
unclear and then once again Jubilee join
me and a kind of a debate framing
meeting so if anyone has any other
topics that they're passionate about
that tends to go against the grain or is
in a contentious issue I think it'd be
fun to have a
a meeting to discuss how how to how you
would phrase that in for goalie bot and
I would find that helpful in my project
I'll go first since a muted first are
going at Stoppers I know it orders time
I am my own project solution racing and
jublia starts a lot of fires so this
last week I had a solution raising on
history we came up with a really cool
idea for creating a like a living
storytelling for especially to collect
the information from elders before they
they pass and so I'm busy working but
not on that because I don't actually
work on the solution amazing ideas that
are generated but on doing that for my
daughter
with her living grandparents and just
trying to figure out what questions I
can ask them five or six questions in
comment and asking all four of them I
have also I met with Carrie's friend
abet so that was a amazing conversation
and having more just witnessing the
people coming on board to game be and to
my project and the interweaving of all
of our lives is just amazing and I'm
excited by that and my fire alarm keeps
going off randomly so not excited by
that
but that is my update if Leo's not able
to be in the hot seat
I could take it for solution raising if
no one else has all right I guess I can
go next wiki election is it's in the
functional prototype phase I've been
working with Mateus to sort of you know
start off with a very simple framework
and then we'll keep adding on features
or the end goal is to get it to
something that it's a bit easier to show
people to concept cuz it's actually
doing you know maybe 20 25 percent of
what the end product will hopefully do
right now it's only storing people
organizations and then people's roles
within those organizations so the next
step is going to be tracking legislation
allowing there to be just some very
basic sort of summary of what the
legislation is about what I've got I
think like five or six topics that we'll
be able to track a score for on that
legislation
and then also tracking help help people
voted on their legislation while in a
certain role and with the goal being
that their vote would then affect you
know sort of the same kind of scoring
system on that that person's record
based on if they voted for or against
something then it would you know flip
the the score so if something was you
know bad for the environment and you
voted against it then that would end up
being a positive for the environment on
your record and that'll be sort of the
first piece of the prototype that's more
than just like records in a table
because it's actually sort of
summarizing some underlying records so
that is the next step and I finally
actually got the project officially
started with with Matus at work which
have been taking a while to get going
but that is is rolling now okay well
finally got stored on the Drupal and
Anniston site and everything else so
getting a state with that and yeah he
that has grieved to be the octopus
Jubilee also is a Unreal Engine
confidence coming up on the 14th which
is flee so it did a bit of 3d modeling
when I was at college last time although
I'm not really used Unreal Engine for
thinking about maybe building a virtual
worlds as a game out of that story's
bubbling up beneath the surface
went for a coffee with the neighbor
today turns out to be an economist so am
talking about donuts he cannot make so
now he wants to get hands-on with stuff
so I told her about what we do in he's
interested in that so that was good
first I was supposed to wonder they've
risen about 20 odd years since ilithyia
so him yeah so maybe killer in Irvine is
this a good thing so that's basically
all I've got to that aim and I can't
think of anything else just still trying
to have more conversations with people
in the group and now so does they please
Peter
he's a finance guy from Australia so
more on the lines off right what I'm
supposed to carry
as well so yeah so I think if we can get
us all I have round table or something
for the Australians em in the group and
happy toes so they come to me into that
because I can stay up late to go back to
work anyway so and I can't think of
anything else just now apart from I'm
still trying to so they get more people
to have a chat and see what what and and
I don't know who else to do with that
you know apart from book them yes I have
a couple quick things for to blee and
Adriel so babe before we pick a hot seat
so Jubilee I just I just thought of when
I saw your thing have you have you seen
StoryCorps Story CRPS so they're an
organization I don't know if they're
us-based or what but they're they help
people record conversations with their
elders and I think they even have
suggested formats and stuff so that
might be something yeah you can check
out and if you can't find it let me know
and I can find a link
they've been featured on several NPR
podcasts in the past with their stories
that people recorded and just on a side
note a friend of mine her mother had a
stroke and we weren't sure if whether
her speech is gonna come back and that
person had been wanting to record down
the stories and I've been wanting to do
it with my mom as well so I do encourage
people to do it now if you if you have
someone like that in your life that I
don't know if I want my dad's stories
but my own stories yet and then for
Adrian I was just thinking probably not
in this level of the prototype but you
know we were talking about how the
legislation like if they voted for it
well sometimes they voted against that
legislation because it really didn't do
what it said so you know naively we we
might be saying oh that they voted
against the environment really that vote
against that legislation was for it
that's actually a place where reason
score might be able to fit
so I don't want to overcomplicate your
issue but when you think about it that
would we would say oh this piece of
legislation is about at the environment
right but then you can come underneath
it and say oh it's not very important
because it would have been effective or
or it was rewritten and committee or you
know all those other reasons or he voted
against it because this other one and
then that would affect roll up to the
top score so whenever you want to have
that discussion not allowed to enjoy
that sure yeah that might be cool for
now you know I right now I just want
like bare bones like it initially I'm
not even doing versions of legislation
there's just a single table still
written like the different records which
means theoretically you could see like
the same piece of legislation and have
three or four times whereas in the
actual version you know we end up doing
different versioning and who wrote it
and what changed and stuff like that but
yeah that could end up being cool to
help see if we can figure out that weird
mm like the minutiae of the legislation
where it's like why is it or isn't it
and maybe fully aligned with that
certain category which is of course how
reality actually works
the prototype won't be great for that
part of it because you can't always boil
down some legislation to just oh it's
great for this and that for this end of
story yeah one of those I might have
just encountered because there was
something way worse than the 7-eleven
thing which was actually I we go today
on July 4th there was a group of white
people who tried to lynch a black eye
now that's the story and seems to be
what's that's coming out but in that
story without juicier
um I guess a few years ago they tried to
make lynching a hate crime and it wasn't
passed through Congress and I I'm like
how is Lin Chi not the first hate crime
how is that not the reason the
legislation exists that maybe there were
other reasons maybe it was a other but
no I'm not gonna give him the benefit of
the doubt it's it like who goes how does
that go through and not get passed
unanimously that of course Lynch if I
think the later version did okay well
good yeah
were hearing that certain politician was
sort of you know on record saying why he
didn't support it and then I remember
reading a couple of days later that
actually had passed unanimously so there
might have been something in there sort
of like this one
there was some weird language or it was
just you didn't support it because you
know which is then like she's been on
the hundred percent Pro lynching is of
course a hate crime side that I just
hear that and of course any politician
who wouldn't it wasn't a hundred percent
for it was therefore one percent against
it and it's like that's clearly not the
truth and then even if they are someone
who has whatever yeah being able to
bring with you election and the recent
score together in that matter I think
would be beautiful for those things that
are definitely more more nuanced even
though it doesn't sound like it could
possibly be nuanced yeah well and then
it's like even with all the stuff being
added for like the PPP loans in the US
and and that sort of thing your people
voting against it because it's like the
state of purpose is great but then all
the underlying stuff everyone is
sneaking in their pet project and a
whole bunch of you know pork and all
that stuff where their groups voting
against it because you're like yeah this
isn't what they're saying it is which i
think is very common in legislation
which is where it gets difficult but
yeah in my case out of the scope of this
particular sort of phase of the
prototype because that's going be very
deep in something we're broke right now
it's just trying to be a proof of
concept but yeah it's not quite as easy
as the photo type is trying you have to
be and i what bit barely talked because
he keeps trying to unmute himself to I
was just I just wanted to agree okay
that's good so does anyone want to be in
the hot seat no but I've just got
something to say and I noticed on one of
the post-harvest in quickly mentioned
that we might have some psycho
technology projects going on in the
project group I'm not aware of anybody
doing them so far and I don't know
whether you know of anybody doing them
because then I think well it's always
okay right right okay
elegy is a very like broad category
right so if it's not sense-making its
basics pizza got like and sense-making
it's like oh technology as well right so
it's like well what is the definition of
that there's like getting be somewhat
definition of that but anything that
brings people together and helps with
intra or interpersonal is oh my god I
don't know anybody scared that you know
a bead so it is it though whether
someone's doing them I wasn't too sure
about the way and that you know I mean
so in other sense because I thought well
if someone comes and as a look and you
might not notice it straight away or
whatever yeah so anyway so that's
alright because I've got to be freaked
out because I thought we're gonna get
all these people coming looking and
they're gonna go talking about yeah I
think kind of all of our projects touch
on psycho tech but they also so it
depends on the person there are I think
certain certain technology proposals
that people have made and maybe they're
wondering whether we're doing anything
to facilitate those which jubblies
project might would probably fit under
several of us yeah I feel like here as
emotional dojos also anything done by
the stoah rebel wisdoms doing their
stuff future thinkers doing their stuff
that is all psycho technology they're
just not under the game B umbrella
because they have their own brand and
they have you know like they have their
own following and they have their own so
they're not rubble wisdom trying to play
game B it's they're just playing baby
and you know the rebel wisdom is that
make sense for this we're kind of under
because we don't have a fan base because
we don't have that like we're kind of
under it like for saying we need to make
a psycho technology seems very game B
but like just making it seems even more
game be like just play just do it let's
like what you where does it go
I'm a little worried about the new
people coming into game B as I'm always
worried about everyone um like I'm doing
the welcoming post and it's generally
like fifty people each time and even I'd
say three or four months ago when
post would happen everyone would
interact with it because you'd be
looking for people right and the issue
is the first generation or you know
Jordan Hall and Jim rutting them but
like the first generation of people in
we've all found our people and I don't
know how much more we can be like go out
find your people come join us do this
without cuz I'm you know like I'm not
gonna when those posts would first come
out I would look through them for people
who I had stuff in common with talk to
them to interview them to do that I know
Kerry he's kind of taking on that role
at the moment but there is an issue I
feel like be almost everyone who did
that because we were all so hungry for
looking for people and now the people
are coming in looking for something to
do not really getting to do like seeing
that there are all of these things going
on even if we tell them and at the same
time like it looks like the game view
Facebook is dead like it looks like
there's no like you but like I post this
on I know what interacted with it right
because that's not what this is like
you're not like how to get the next
cohort to interconnect with each other
right instead of looking for them to
need to go I don't know but that's maybe
just not like firing start or do
anything do you think might have to do
with a separation of game be into all
the different groups like you know how
old game be it was a little bit noisy
where it because there wasn't a group
for projects people were never they
inevitably posting their projects in the
game be group and now that that becomes
a separate group it is sort of quieter
and it's not I guess as clear what
should go there what shouldn't go there
and I guess it's not as a natural of a
place for the conversations that might
drive that like ooh that person or not
have the same goals or that person is
working on something that I'm interested
in let's connect yeah absolutely but
it's also one it used to only be like 25
people who are admitted each week now
it's 50 at least and because there's
like there's partly the algorithm partly
just like no one seems to be interacting
with it besides the people who are just
coming in in which case they're putting
what they has but no one's reading it I
don't even know if they're reading each
other's right which is what I when I
first it was like oh look at all these
cool people who can I connect with
I think it's just every few weeks
posting that connect with each other
find people you have something in common
with you're in the driver's seat go and
find people but good good we could add
to the introduction and also that may be
important enough for Kari to include
that on the welcome message although I
do think to Kerry's earlier discussions
maybe it was last week I think there's a
lot of people that are just kind of this
is a per for a interest so we're gonna
get a lot of people coming in that
aren't gonna interact and I think that
that's okay I wish there was a way in
facebook that you could follow a group
without saying you're a member but
apparently that's not a feature well
also says there's a lot of people come
in and said no they're looking for
projects to get involved with but I
think I think because I don't know if
the because there doesn't seem to be
right cuz one are all posting about our
project all the time I know you've got
the things you think and I don't know
whether it's obvious so I suppose one
wants to direct to be get set up I think
that would be a lot better for people to
actually see and go through and stuff
like that but as I said there's a lot of
people coming in who actually want to
when I'm so they look for projects to
get involved with and it's a bit
difficult because cuz I'm I don't know
what else that'll interested in it's a
bit difficult to try and connect them
with each other and why as I said that
you know like kind of given up sending
messages because like I don't get no
response
so I just try to give us all went right
okay ASP every time on the people the
way I've chatted with so far and so like
if I find stuff I'll post it for them
and we had it as far as saying I thought
I don't know
and what else to do really to encourage
conversation or things or all you may
think I don't want to post up because it
might not be so like you know I mean so
it's a bit it's a bit of a fine line you
know because what you don't want is
people posting things that are kind of
relevant to any of the projects because
he can do that in the game be
main space you know me and if it'll be
shots and conversations and discussions
ok I'm more talking with the main space
the main space where there's people
coming in and they're looking for where
to go then they join the side groups and
there's way too many side groups some of
which are basically dead and so there's
only a handful of them that have
anything really going on it anyway if
this is a game be thing but I should
probably just need to break up with the
events and be like like like I want
people to find what I found it it's like
they can't just nest and here they can
right here come to a roundtable no
problem jump in but most of the of it
isn't necessarily like that it's like
right people already found their their
their partners and their their people to
work with and so we're not as open to
conversation as we used to be like
unless you want to come to Eric's thing
on Tuesday he can't fit you in otherwise
and you know my time also same thing
it's like okay I can't even if I want to
meet with all of these people and more
and more of us are getting filled up so
that makes it's like that's kind of our
Jim not Jim right Jordan Hall was like
in September when I started that he was
willing to meet with people and that was
great and now I don't know if he would
be because his time is fulfilled up and
that's like what's happening to Nick
Eric Bentley you know do you need like
it's like it starts your time starts to
fill up and you don't have any more
capacity either
like and that is very game B game a like
it's there's something in there of right
the next cohort has to come in and
interconnect with each other and they're
still gonna not put the one before and
the one before that and one before that
but there's something about it like yes
if something's not getting done you do
it you can active each other don't
and yet when there's two thousand people
like there's a different feeling to
there being two hundred versus two
thousand where with two hundred you're
like right what are we baking in two
thousand you like you haven't made it
yet I don't understand how did you not
make it yeah like right because so and
also Carrie I think the project list the
directory is sufficient enough that if
someone's asking I think it'd be good to
post that as a response to their comment
or the to their post
I think I don't know how many why do we
have like five projects in there now but
it's a start
mm yeah yeah what I said pleasure
posting things on Thursday I was open
more people was actually shipping and
actually post more about what they're up
to enough but as I said it's just
getting the initial conversations going
seems to be taking a bit more time than
I thought it would with new people
joining and and as I said them it's just
as I said some of them don't introduce
themselves and some of them do so I know
so so I've got a kind to wait for them
to introduce themselves to find out more
about Gregor's people being there and I
didn't even know they were there and it
used to like maybe commented and that's
what that's how I see them now and so
I'll kind of pounce on them after that
trying to see if I can fix up a chat
well I think that's a now people don't
seem to want to want to voice chat or
video chat so I don't know whether
that's just the thing that we're gonna
have to get used to because they come
well I won't look for chats you know I
mean sorry
that's wrong yeah I mean everyone's
different that's part of what I'm
dealing with
I'm smoke everything it's like how I
make a friendly one it's not gonna be
for everyone
it just isn't it's gonna be for people
who want to have video chat and I can
make it so that you can't you either do
or don't record it but do words that you
don't I mean like if it's like well
these people are having their own video
and these people are having it by text
and these people having it by
conversation until that naturally
emerges yeah does anyone want to have
anything for the hot seat or should I do
solution easy I'm fine with that
okay so um so Tracy and I'm still in the
process of writing up three different
articles one of which is how it
currently looks which is just the me
doing Wednesday morning solution
raisings people come or they don't
they've now switched onto zoom so why
can't I can accommodate up to a hundred
people at that session so we can switch
into smaller groups and have them but
what I really want is other people
hosting solution raising I want there to
be a way that we together can vote on
what
topic is for that week so that if you
want to there's a common topic between
all the solution reasons I would love
there to be people like to different
paths one of which is people who like
myself want to host hundred people
solution Aires things like up to a
hundred people and so they just take a
timeslot and they can use my zoom
account and be a mega host and do that
or if that doesn't work for you finding
on your own or facilitated through
solution raising and finding a group of
people to meet with weekly or monthly so
that you're getting more of a real
connection over time right so one that's
like a drop in get randomly assigned to
whoever it is and then as you find
people or as you have people in your own
life you can start to have a weekly one
to add to and then people can record or
not record them if you come up with
something powerful then you can submit
it to something like Reddit and get
uploaded and when we get the top three
we can then have like an official vote
with just the members which there aren't
any yet but like just the members just
the people who have in fact said yes we
have our own group or we come to the
minute we post the men and ones we come
to the metal ones sorry may go no better
I don't call them um yeah I don't even
know what I'm exactly looking for except
that I'm trying to figure out how to do
that within my capacity how to get other
people on board without like they're not
magically showing up at my door and
asking to do it and I'd really like help
with that okay so are you having enough
participants now that you can't handle
the volume or are you looking for or
which is more important I guess because
I think you mentioned both are we're
looking for other people to generate new
opportunities well no there isn't too
much but I switched over to zoom for the
odd time there was a fifth sixth seventh
person wanting to participate it's
easier to be able to just oh yeah cool
if people showed up let's switch it and
there's one you or all people have to
follow week after week but this is the
first week doing that and it was only
Daniel Carrie and I so it was actually
less the normal Eric told me he wasn't
showing up though um and I think that's
fine
I think that will build and grow as
people show up and they can be put into
groups I don't know quite how to
facilitate that in the moments for any
session I'm part of it's going to be
recorded there can be this the parallel
one that's not recorded but it anyway
that's that's a side note I'm missing
the question are they I guess yeah which
of those what what's the biggest problem
that you would like to solve because you
mentioned quite a few things well the
solution raising itself is powerful
every one of them has come up with a
powerful solution that it's implemented
could move us powerfully forward there's
something about the fact that there's
only four of us having that conversation
that isn't as powerful as if dozens of
people were having the same conversation
and then we could see what's emerging
from all of them and see like the hope
that that would give and so I want to
give individuals the opportunity to
participate if they want to and
Wednesdays at 9:00 a.m. that I'm
available isn't necessarily when
everyone else is available so I want to
be able to offer right at this time to
slot doesn't work for you it's actually
really easy to have one your own I even
have a zoom account come use it right
that like let's pick topics together
let's host them pick pick a time that
works for you in the international time
zones and then and so I know I'm not
answering the question Bentley but all
of it that's like I want to be able to
start multiple so that for people that
the time doesn't work I want them to
have it another time that I don't
necessarily have to facilitate and for
people who come into a mega one doesn't
work I want to give them the option of
like hey if you have three friends you
like a book club I get together every
week host a solution raising so that you
can have the experience of seeing
there's actual possibility out there
that you can do a 10,000 people and a
hundred thousand dollars so it sounds
like the first step though is getting
more people involved and then handling
the logistics of that is that tell them
true I know you want all of it but yeah
yeah I mean if if there's more people
you're right having more people come to
Wednesday so we can break off into
groups and then from that there could be
natural mega hosts and people who emerge
that so yes growing
the Wednesday session so I don't have to
constantly is actually the priority I
saw you on meeting Adria yet something
else
yeah I was good going to agree well one
of the things with the solution raisings
is I'm not sure if this has been
happening I just haven't seen it but I
know in the ones I've taken a pardon
that they were quite interesting but in
the group I never have really seen like
a summary that made it appealing and
sort of explained like here's what was
decided on here's this cool stuff coming
out of it to sort of bait the hook to
make it a bit more like you don't have
to go and watch the full thing to get
the appeal because if you aren't going
to it like there's there's nothing
pulling you to go watch it unless you've
seen previous one so it's costar ting
point in my mind as opposed to if there
were a post where you were like hey
here's I don't know like I think you did
eeeh in reddit of like having people
vote on the ideas and having some form
of like actually listing the ideas and
voting on them or just you know to start
with it's having somebody who was
participating in it or like you or or
someone creating a separate post for hey
we just had this great social and
raising the link will be at the end of
that post but then you might summarize
like here's what we talked about here's
the top three ideas to help sort of you
know that's the the kind of post that I
imagine you would end up with almost
another solution raising in the comments
you know like hey this is all great by
the way we're doing one next week on
this right well now I started trying to
summarize to board me and so maybe if I
got sidetracked and so maybe if I do
this the solution raising ones and just
for a week you are we support we comment
on to each of the solution raisins or
would you rather I did a main comment
and say look if you've missed them the
previous solution raise and say they are
would you want me to do them one at a
time and then for so many underneath the
Lord you want me to because I want to
notice Jubilee is that you post that
there's a solution raisin or sometimes
you don't post the video in the group to
say the
this is what what's done you know I mean
so so it's the walk away to the group
you'll just see the the invite for it
but you don't see the what actually you
know I mean yes so do you want me to
just start putting the videos one by one
only yeah then the awesome yeah by okay
I'll do that then
definitely a summary of what we came up
with I tried with the first sets to go
through and decide what we had come up
with and I because I can't even the
three articles I'm trying to write is
enough for my brain like rising it is
not much fun suit so right I suggest and
Carey would be to first write those out
in a Google Doc or some sort of shared
document because then you can kind of
paste the content or if you want and
that way it's a place that we can get to
to to reuse the content right only to go
watch them all again calls and I would
start with the most recent and work
backwards
yeah or just start with the the next one
maybe yeah for which are we talking
sluice raising or I wish them solution
raisin so what I've doing they said the
one you've just done I'll do that face
Jubilee and I'll post the video this is
what we've got in the you know I mean
and then I'll wake me way backwards and
I'll say look like this and I'll what
I'll do is I'll put a link to the
playlist and then we both all of them on
it under each one and then obviously
they can go and up a log order might
just do one for the playlist and then do
so like somebody's for each of them can
you don't load files in them and their
solution rays and things and then in the
group of solution raisin and you load
files in that so yeah right okay I made
you and it been in solution raised and I
should make you in a minute and see what
you wanted you got that and then a
console so like post things and because
they took because they also find that if
you start posting information about
what you're talking about underneath
then okay sometimes a link doesn't work
like the the slavery one where we went
to the site it didn't work for all the
other things that maybe come out of that
all things that are found afterwards
that are related to that and then that
would kind of bump up what it was but on
what I'll do is I'll post the videos and
then put a summary of all the ones that
we've had and then put links to maybe
follow-up stuff and what people might
want to look at and see if they're
interested in maybe ten and stop into a
project that they could what copies on
now or something like that I think that
would help possibly I'm definitely not
focused like anyone wants to take any of
them and run with them I'm good there's
a reason I'm not is that it doesn't make
sense for for people to do it the whole
point is to like figure out how to do
this and are in a nearly risk-free
together way so that each one is in its
own individual project it's gonna go and
fail and go and fail and go and fail and
one percent of them will succeed it's
like once we get that sister in place
ninety percent of them will succeed
because we have a process to actually go
through to say right it's not just these
four coming up with an idea there's
hundreds of people having conversations
and we've picked the best one and we're
all we know it's the best one because we
kind of all came to it or this amazing
one that no one thought of that yeah you
know that we've heard that that's the
one and that's my hypothesis of what
happens it's not necessarily don't you
give us I try to put up a list to try
and see if there's anybody in a group
and topics see if anyone was in the
group or you know I never got what she
spawns so I don't know what do you want
to make it's about men and I'll kind of
do what I can
I am father says he should it's just
trying to get people to obviously talk
you know I mean because I think people
just join groups and then you forget
then you go off and do something else
and then oh oh oh
the first race is only like 50 people so
there's locked in their feed and they
don't see it I love that's really if we
get a good sort of like summary of
recent topics are like a highlight reel
first
socializing it might also be good just
start doing some of that cross posting
unless it's already happening I'm not
seeing it more cross posting in the
a group where it's not meant to be like
every solution raising gets 18 posts but
if it's meant to be a hey or doing this
cool thing here's some of the awesome
things that have come out of it a 2,000
people in this group if you're
interested you know coming over and join
it and then same thing with the projects
and everything to start trying to use
the game be group more actively to like
pull people to the other groups because
they might just not know that that they
exist they may have just joined the game
B group because they saw it you know on
River wisdom and then they aren't seeing
much in the main group but if they start
seeing more and more content about all
this other stuff so like just kind of
have it be a highlight reel and then III
don't in a previous meeting we had
talked about the game B subreddit I'm
not sure if we've done any work like try
to push people there as well because
that could also be a really good sort of
cross channel posting because it's got
its own ability to sort of have people
you know put them down vote what they
think is interesting if you have your
highlights there then the community can
decide like oh that is a good a good
highlight that sounds cool and then you
know if 10 people do it all of a sudden
now way more people in that separate are
senior okay so I think probably list the
links would I be everything kids and
then Wacom because they wanna find is
that you know if you start posting the
same stuff in each different place
people who are in the same place just go
you know I mean so you've got to try and
make it different for each each you know
not that much difference but when you're
posting stuff if you start imposing the
same content everywhere then you just
broadcast in the same stuff right you
know I mean so and I don't want to be
putting people off before they've even
got going you know I mean cuz I said it
just because well I know what I'm like
when I see stuff that coasted all over
the shop and it's the same thing I'm
just like I'm not even gonna bother you
know I mean I think technically it would
be somewhat different because if you're
you know posting a summary of these
social ratings in this ocean writing
channel it's somebody who's already
indicated their interest so you can
probably go you know a couple
levels deeper in like each post might
just pay hey here's the highlight of
this particular solution raising here
some cool stuff in the game be group I
mean like really top of the waves like
here's three cool ideas and three very
different topics that came out of a
solution raising okay go so price okay
so I think what we need is a social
media qualms then and maybe schedules
and then click that so if we could maybe
whenever get a meeting about a state in
a social media schedule and that most
well yeah I'll just then I'll go to the
solution raisins and I put so many in
and stuff as well so and yeah okay I
think also and finding someone who is
willing to do the highlight reel like
actually just looking through them and
editing I mean like this 30 second clip
would be awesome
and if that's not in someone's
wheelhouse even just having people tag
what they think is awesome right to be
like oh I really like this I really like
that is also helpful and I really don't
like asking people to do things like
that people are looking for projects
there are people with that skill in game
be and it's something that would take me
all day it would take somebody else I'm
you besides the hour sitting through it
five minutes right right
can you don't right I've got access to
your account so stuff and I've also got
Premiere Pro which I do some video
editing if you wanted me to so maybe if
I just get the solutions at the end bit
rather than the first bit or do you want
the fit which would you rather four
three three bit beats bits of each or
would you rather this is the kinds of
well solutions you just want the
solution and bit I think it's whatever
speaks to the person enemy right so like
whatever um the generally it's gonna be
the third part it's gonna be the part
where actually generating ideas and the
parks and the pieces of that that are
powerful and amazing but at some point
I'm sure it'll be like focusing on
solution areas in itself here
are the three parts we go through and
why we go through them showing someone
venting and being like oh and then
seeing the beautiful future and then
seeing the thing that we come up with
the ends but for now it's just yeah the
solutions that are generated there are
powerful right okay so I tell you what
right you like what you're doing and
then three blogs and then I'll take that
and then I'll do the add the highlight
reel from what you've written because
they're not love me and but for now I'll
just kind of if you make me enough men
in the troop and also how would you
download the cuz I've never downloaded
anything from any videos from YouTube is
that an easy thing to do I think channel
depending on the settings on the YouTube
channel yeah and just there's a download
button like I can't remember it might be
hidden underneath something but on that
page I think so you can just download it
the other option is Jubilee can give you
access to her channel and then you could
there's an editor built-in to YouTube
it's for making clips so that's pretty
easy to use and I think would be a
little quicker than downloading and
reuploading yeah it's just I don't you
know I'm very worried about you know
when you attend something that you like
make it so class of it I'm doing it yeah
you can't you can't edit the original
you can't change the original video
because youtube doesn't allow that so
there's no chance of you over right hand
because YouTube once you post something
you're not allowed to make changes to
the video itself and then I wanted to
kind of talk a bit about getting more
participants because I kind of think
about when you want to do that you want
to have like a link of somewhere that
that people can send other people and do
invites and also if you ever wanted to
do paid advertising you'd use that and
make sure that when they go there it has
a very clear call to action at
description and call to action now the
solution raisings homepage might have
that it might be that
patien and then an easy way for people
to subscribe to know what's going on
so maybe facebook.com slash groups last
solution raising is all of that but it
might be interesting to kind of look at
it and say does this really accomplish
that if people come here is it clear why
they would join the group and then I
don't know for losing people because
there are some people that aren't on
Facebook and better but you know
creating a website and having a
newsletter that you sign up but then
you'd have to post the announcements on
the newsletter as long as Facebook so
it's a lot of it's a lot of manual work
which we're about to overload carry on
all the admin work we're giving her so
but those are just my thought that's the
thought process I do when we say we want
kind of more people
that's greaseless the buts yeah one
extra note on that that kind of combines
with a previous topic is if we're trying
to find cool clips and we're trying to
get people interested it might be cool
actually almost have like a contest of
like hey if you're going through
previous ocean ratings don't just go
watch them your goal is to find like
your snippet that really stands out to
you and then if we hit you know
eventually have something like a reddit
you can have a single post saying hey
you know we're looking for the best you
know 10 to 30 second clip and this
solution raising people can post sort of
you know their their comments up all
from this time stamped at this timestamp
and then the initial link can actually
take you right to that YouTube video
starting at that time stamp and then
tell you when to sort of stop and say
that's the part and then people can
upvote and downvote and say like oh I
really like that one and then you you
know that gives them also sort of an
excuse to get some reddit points which
you know that's what half of that
community's about but then also it
helped like it gives people a reason
it's a more sort of it's a direct call
to action that they can actually do as
opposed to hey go watch this library of
you know 30 hour long videos and yeah so
think of social media and post and plan
and schedule look fun and all sorts of
plans
okay um yeah so right so Jimmy if you
make us out minute that loop then and
I'll I'll try and see if I can wake me
be Kelly munching sounds awesome
I don't know if we also kind of
mentioned you may have stepped away that
making her inviting her to be an admin
of the YouTube channel if she's not
already of Jubilee create something
amazing which is which by the way fYI
didn't update I changed the invite
YouTube channel to be let's see though I
did to show under smart
oh she's Bob no and I don't know whether
you want to make me the same on together
tap as well so I can you know likes as I
said I couldn't remove things I noticed
that you haven't put the things into
playlists and that's what i'm not i'm
although can i can i add her two
together tech because i like its Adriel
channels so you can try if you've
already okay so I can don't mess up our
30 subscribers Yoko Bach ago just be
water it'll be me going you know because
I just noticed like there's a lot of
stuff that isn't in playlists I'd
obviously if you you wanted to show
people you know you want it as updated
as possible and of everything in there
otherwise because then that'll lead to
all the stuff that you want to watch
what been watching you know I mean so
yeah so I think I need to develop a
social media strategy their name what's
out there I think I've got some ducks on
that on how best to put one together so
I'll em yeah I'll do that and other
things as well you know okay sounds good
yeah the other the other thing would be
cuz why not why not on certain t-virus
oh nothing
so when wanting people to start their
own solution raising group because
there's what I'm doing which is picking
a new topic every week because I don't
want to talk about the same topic
weekend
I'm part of the conversation and you
know even if there were hundreds of
people have any conversation on food I
would have the conversation on food
again but right now anyway as people
come in and they're starting their own
groups having the same six topics that
they talk about so that they're talking
about food and then they're talking
about shelter or they're talking about
the government they're talking about
like picking a few different very broad
topics some that are more focused on
your own individual life is some that
are giant like prisons having those be
so that as people are starting their
posting their own solutions and coming
up with their best idea on food their
best ID on prisons their best idea on
the ones have ready done and as per
usually need to probably pick one what
is it like either we're doing a
different topic every week and therefore
that's what we're voting on or hey here
the same ten topics we're gonna keep
talking about these again and again
until more people are joining and more
people are you know I was just thinking
it's it's possible to control the
YouTube player so maybe a little side
project I can do is to create a YouTube
clip playlist tool so it'd be a website
you can go and create a playlist of just
clips rather than YouTube only lets you
do the whole videos in a playlist and
you could do start and stop times if
your JavaScript if you are doing that
I'm very interested because that is very
easily overlap with benefits that's
probably where I got the idea is from
wiki election so yeah so maybe maybe now
that we have two needs for that it'd be
worth time taking a weekend project and
and whipping something up and make sure
it plugs into what Martucci is doing on
a wiki election and I've always kind of
wanted to do that but it could be
community curated so I think it would
just be a tool that you could use for
any of it like all it is is you're sort
of saying here's the YouTube video
here's the start time and end time and
then it just plays that and so you could
use that on a new site you could use
that here you could use that on wiki
election you could robably use it on
reason score yeah and I also have
thought about
a aggregate training site where he'd put
together classes with clips from other
website mmm YouTube would be a start of
that and then it also write the blog
post and to complete this specific
section anyways so it's lots of use for
that I mean if it's a plug-in you can
use for anything and it's just a URL for
a video wherever the video is stop start
time that's huge if it can be plugged
into everything else cuz yeah then you
can use it for education you can use it
for you know yeah the way you said that
actually I figured out a way to do it
extremely low cost because if it's in
the URL the start and end time in the
YouTube video I can have a page pop-up
and Auto generate it okay huh now I got
I got a did some weather app and then I
got a YouTube clip yeah because you were
like oh we're doing the weather thing
for wait what is it that changes
throughout the day is it like air
quality sunlight like what is it you're
doing it for it is all of that so yeah
so and I looked online and no no seems
to do this but it would it would take
into account the humidity the
temperature sunlight cloudiness
maybe air quality if I can get that data
I'm not sure if I can and wind because
my mom is trying to find time to walk
and she's trying to do evenings cuz it's
windier but it's I'm trying to tell her
it's really hot in the in Texas at 6
p.m. that's look that's literally the
hottest part of the day but for some
reason she doesn't think so so but
anyways it would it would take the hours
of the day and rank them from top to
bottom of what's most comfortable based
on the temperature it would have a
default but you would then be able to
adjust the algorithm to say oh I don't
care if it's raining I'll walk or run in
the rain so it's just a little bitty app
that that and it only worked for the
United States because I'm unless someone
can help me find though the weather
service data for the other countries so
it hits the NOAA website pulls down the
XML one and go do the calculations and
and rank each hour in the day and then
sort them by that hour
maybe something our father could use for
if it included air quality as well
pollen count if you want to try it in
Canada you can check out whether gzc a
that's a fairly decent
weather service provided by the
Government of Canada and like looking at
now for for owen city and its there's
actually a more detailed view somewhere
oh yeah if you scroll down it goes into
say that again whether or not what well
whether or not GC for Government of
Canada yeah so whether out GC dossier
and then like here an example in the
private channel put in that's a link to
Calgary and then you can do a search for
it and stuff and that's a it's you know
a fairly consistent and it's all these
cities so I mean D us probably makes
more sense because there's a lot more
demand for because there's more than ten
times the number of people if you're
also looking for an alternate DEA's
horse well yeah mostly because that's my
mom's here right I don't care about you
people know yeah it's also like having
one place cuz it's like all of everyone
has weather and it's basically the same
like me even though I'm saying
Fahrenheit and Celsius it like having
one leg even if all the governments were
doing and having one place where they
then filter through so that it then
creates it in too late because I've like
use Google's information it's just
easier but then it's Google's like it's
like using and then using it from that
point so that it is international like
there's anyway we don't need to solve
that but you know if you can just solve
that Bentley yeah it's great the thing
that's oh we need Google what's taking
so long
yeah Jubilee can I ask you to start any
more fires so that's me now if you tell
my brain matters just gonna do it's like
asking the Sun not to shine good day no
fires
I usually don't start fires on the
weekends
they see this start on Wednesday for
some reason if you arson this is gonna
be very interesting huh
out of context but I just got this
cartoon okay so I said like to
everything yeah it's funny cuz the
Jubilee um x-men light sparks and I
always thought that was like the
stupidest thing ever like I'm like
that's the worst oh my god that's me
actually it's like and it's just that
it's like a spark it's not even like a
full-blown fire otherwise I would have
saved the world already it's like
there's one here's anyone there's anyone
who would have thought as you start
working on like that snippet project I'm
definitely interested in because it
sounds like all the parts of it with
like the different video sources to
being able to do it to articles and
possibly studies like that's yeah big
part of okay well yeah I so yeah if I if
I get these other little projects out
the way I might schedule a meeting with
you and we can just make sure that I'm
aware of your requirements that so
whatever I build can be reused right I
think I have it but it'd be good to chat
over again just to make sure before I
set fingers to keyboard
so right we're near the our mark this
was a good hour I have things to do
except I don't want to start I don't
want to work on fires that were to
started and start new ones multiple ones
that's not true I really like solution
raising there's something about it that
is it's holding you to it um and thank
God for Kerry my goodness alright so
I'll make you admin Kerry I'm gonna work
on those articles that I've been working
on for weeks now and yet haven't
actually typed out there are my
whiteboard an outline format and I will
figure out this week we'll figure out
how to like create more people into the
Wednesday session before I try to open
up all the other time slots and all the
other other things and when there's more
people there it'll be a natural
progression people that keep showing up
and want to be part of the meta host so
yeah you just really need polling gate
like that there's people there but
there's no engagement so we need to find
a way of engaging people that are there
and then obviously if somebody you might
want to call then get them in and
keeping them engaged as well I think
that's that's the main thing cuz I've
been focusing on the project of trying
to get the engagement there going yeah
and which is slowly common for not you
know I mean um because obviously if I'm
not post and if you you know a couple of
things you know and it's nothing getting
close to people think there's not
nothing so if you try and get and that's
why I've been tagging useful stuff is
the people who have chatted to because
it's good for me when i chat to them and
then I find out what they're up to and
then I can get getting more stuff on
that so I think more engagement and I
think maybe talking to the people in be
getting to know that people in the
solution raising and finding out their
time people it's basically shows up to
the solution itself but that's the other
what I might do that is not quite
starting a new fire but holding this is
starting a second time slot and we
talked about it works for the Australian
people and works for me mostly
but getting someone else who's willing
to be that meta host or that time slot
for when I'm not able to function at a
later time so I'm the day
and then if there's two time slots one
we are doing the same topic so then how
do we decide on that topic me right now
until look until we have a way of like
doodle poll and there's enough people
showing up that they want to vote on it
what's the next one
or offering it in solution raising but
yeah I like the idea of starting the
second one for solution raising so that
even if we're it's only one topic a week
and even if there's only three or two or
three people to show up in each of the
sessions we're having at least two a
week so that we there's two different
ones that people are attending and then
see do they come up with the same
solution do they call a service right oh
yeah oh you're talking to me about on
Thursday do you want to mention to air
whether she'd be interested in because I
think he'd be interested in doing them
with Yvette as well you know so if you
want to mention to me that that you know
you you're interested in doing them and
ask her would she be interested in doing
them with ya
you know because I think it would be
good for there as well and you know I
mean so I think that'd be good so if
you're asking if she'd be interested in
doing them and I think that I think she
is more available later in the day which
is perfect well I know she said she this
group a name she's not going anymore so
that's free there of some time and that
you know I mean but as it says if you
just check with that because I think it
might be good for air to get into the
swing of things as well
you know I mean and then she gets to
meet other people listen uh I know I
made me you know I mean I'm not I don't
know whether she wants to join game be
or not but I'd rather just she just
wants to do what she wants to do
basically in core as I said if you'd
asked yeah and and then cuz I think that
was also a nice to have a three-way
conversation with the idea PI to mainly
after spider than the octopus if that's
okay really graphic for those three okay
I was gonna call it the coven anyway yes
we will so we can say goodbye to YouTube
and Facebook go say you see you next
week for the together tech
board meeting and the roundtable on
Saturday